You just turn around and walk away like that.
넌 그냥 돌아서면 돼 그리고 그렇게 떠나세요.
[Episode 6: The more veiled the truth, the clearer the mind]
[6회 : 진실은 가려질수록, 마음이 맑아질수록]
You just turned around and walked away like that.
방금 돌아섰잖아 그리고 그렇게 떠났습니다.
It wasn't easy for me to find you.
당신을 찾는 것이 나에게는 쉽지 않았습니다.
I'm not letting you go this time.
이번에는 당신을 보내지 않을 것입니다.
He Xiangyong!
허샹용!
You've got the wrong person.
사람을 잘못 찾아오셨습니다.
No, I'm not.
아니요, 그렇지 않습니다.
I can feel it.
나는 그것을 느낄 수 있다.
You are He Xiangyong.
당신은 He Xiangyong입니다.
You are He Xiangyong!
당신은 He Xiangyong입니다!
Yeah.
응.
I'm as bad as him.
나도 그 사람만큼 나쁘다.
As useless as him.
그 사람만큼 쓸모없어요.
We can't do anything right.
우리는 아무것도 제대로 할 수 없습니다.
We just drag others down
그냥 다른 사람들을 끌어내리면 돼
and make them clean up our mess.
그리고 그들이 우리의 혼란을 정리하게 해주세요.
Don't say that.
그렇게 말하지 마세요.
We're nothing but dead weight.
우리는 죽은 무게에 지나지 않습니다.
Listen to me.
내 말을 들어보세요.
I'm saying
내 말은
that you're the only one who understands me.
당신이 유일한 사람이라는 걸 나를 이해해주는 사람.
You gave me the best birthday gift in the world.
넌 나에게 최고의 생일 선물을 줬어 세계에서.
That sea turtle drawing...
저 바다거북 그림...
Shut up!
입 다물어!
You have no right to mention it.
당신은 그것을 언급할 권리가 없습니다.
I...
나는...
He's just like that drawing.
그 사람이 그 그림과 똑같거든요.
He's already been ripped apart
그 사람은 이미 찢어졌어
and left to rot!
그리고 썩어 버렸어요!
Got it?
알았어요?
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
I should have protected you back then.
그때 내가 당신을 보호했어야 했는데.
It was my fault.
그것은 내 잘못이었습니다.
I'm so sorry.
정말 죄송해요.
Chen Haowei.
첸 하오웨이.
Sorry.
죄송합니다.
Don't tell me this now.
지금은 나에게 말하지 마세요.
I'm not in the mood to think about it.
나는 그것에 대해 생각할 기분이 아니다.
I've accepted reality a long time ago.
나는 오래 전부터 현실을 받아들였다.
The whole world hates me.
온 세상이 나를 미워합니다.
No one likes me.
아무도 나를 좋아하지 않습니다.
Thanks, everyone.
고마워요, 여러분.
I like you.
좋아해요.
He Xiangyong.
허샹용.
Are you crazy, Chen Haowei?
미쳤어요, Chen Haowei?
Yeah.
응.
I'm crazy.
나는 미쳤다.
I've been crazy looking for you all these years.
미친듯이 당신을 찾아다녔어요 몇 년 동안.
Loving you has driven me mad.
당신을 사랑하는 것이 나를 미치게 만들었습니다.
Do you dare to go crazy with me, just once?
감히 나에게 미쳐버릴 셈이냐? 딱 한번?
He Xiangyong!
허샹용!
Chen Haowei, let go of me!
Chen Haowei, 나를 놓아주세요!
Don't disappear again.
다시는 사라지지 마세요.
Let go of me!
날 놔줘!
Chen Haowei!
첸 하오웨이!
You...
당신은...
Let go of me!
날 놔줘!
[Wishing Upon the Shooting Stars]
[별똥별에 소원을 빌어요]
Where is He Xiangyong?
허샹용은 어디에 있나요?
Here we are.
여기 있습니다.
Let's have more drinks!
술을 더 마시자!
Here we are. You should get some rest.
여기 있습니다. 좀 쉬어야 해요.
I'm heading home.
나는 집으로 향하고 있다.
No way. You're not going anywhere.
안 돼요. 당신은 아무데도 가지 않을 것입니다.
Are you a koala or something?
당신은 코알라인가 뭔가인가?
I'm...
나는...
a big wolf.
큰 늑대.
Well,
음,
then I guess that makes me Little Red Riding Hood.
그럼 그게 날 그렇게 만드는 것 같아 작은 빨간 승마모.
No, you're not.
아니요, 그렇지 않습니다.
You're a gift that fell from a shooting star.
당신은 선물이에요 별똥별에서 떨어진 것입니다.
The gift that happened to land right on me.
일어난 선물 나에게 바로 착륙하기 위해.
So you're really not letting me go, huh?
그럼 정말 날 가만두지 않겠다는 거지?
Don't you like me?
당신은 나를 좋아하지 않습니까?
If you like me, then why would you leave?
내가 마음에 든다면 왜 떠나겠습니까?
It's so warm.
너무 따뜻해요.
I'm so happy.
정말 기뻐요.
I wish we could be together like this
우리 이렇게 함께 있었으면 좋겠어
every day.
매일.
You won't regret it?
후회하지 않을 건가요?
I don't know.
모르겠습니다.
I'm afraid I might lose control.
통제력을 잃을까봐 두렵습니다.
This way, you won't.
이렇게 하면 그렇지 않습니다.
I can't take it anymore.
더 이상 참을 수 없습니다.
Can't take what?
무엇을 가져갈 수 없습니까?
It tickles.
간지러워요.
Wait.
기다리다.
What are you doing?
뭐하세요?
You kissed me like that.
당신은 나에게 그렇게 키스했습니다.
And now you're asking me what I'm doing?
그런데 지금 내가 뭘 하고 있는지 묻는 겁니까?
No.
아니요.
Next time.
다음번.
Li Wanzhe.
리완체.
Dudu, stop it, okay?
두두야 그만해 알았지?
He really can't hold his liquor.
그 사람은 정말 술을 참을 수가 없어요.
Please.
제발.
Chen Haowei.
첸 하오웨이.
How did we get back to the guesthouse yesterday?
우리는 어떻게 게스트하우스로 돌아왔나요? 어제?
Right.
오른쪽.
Did I bring you back?
내가 당신을 다시 데려왔나요?
What are you talking about?
무슨 얘기를 하는 건가요?
It was more like I brought you back.
마치 내가 당신을 다시 데려온 것 같았어요.
Whatever.
무엇이든.
I'm thirsty.
목이 말라요.
Rock, paper, scissors. Loser gets the water.
바위, 종이, 가위. 패자가 물을 얻습니다.
I've prepared fish soup and tea for you.
생선 수프와 차를 준비했어요.
They're for your hangover.
숙취 해소용이에요.
Drink them all.
모두 마셔보세요.
The pot calls the kettle black.
냄비는 주전자를 검정색이라고 부릅니다.
Mr. He.
그 씨.
We...
우리는...
didn't cause any trouble yesterday, did we?
어제는 아무 문제도 일으키지 않았는데, 우리는 그랬나요?
Why don't you take a guess?
추측해 보는 게 어때요?
Pot.
냄비.
I'll show you.
보여드릴게요.
You're going further and further out.
당신은 점점 더 멀리 나가고 있습니다.
Watch out!
조심하세요!
What's that?
그게 뭐야?
What is that?
저게 뭐에요?
What do you see?
무엇이 보이나요?
Why are there two people up ahead?
앞에 왜 두 사람이 있는 걸까요?
Who are they?
그들은 누구입니까?
Why are they lying here?
그들은 왜 여기에 누워 있습니까?
No.
아니요.
This way.
이쪽으로.
Don't throw up.
토하지 마세요.
Oh, come on.
아, 어서.
Why are you throwing up like that?
왜 그렇게 토하는 거야?
My clothes!
내 옷!
They are ruined.
그들은 망가졌습니다.
You need to take them to the laundry for me.
당신은 그들을 가져 가야합니다 나를 위해 세탁소에.
Take it easy.
진정하세요.
Anyway, that's what happened.
어쨌든 그런 일이 일어났습니다.
And you said you would take care of him.
그리고 당신이 그 사람을 돌봐주겠다고 하더군요.
Mr. He, I'm sorry.
그 사람 씨, 죄송해요.
We won't
우린 안 할 거야
drink that much next time.
다음에는 그 만큼 마셔라.
Forget it.
잊어버리세요.
I guess
아마
everyone's been feeling down lately.
요즘 다들 기분이 안 좋아졌어.
You guys finish the fish porridge.
여러분 생선죽을 완성하세요.
Then get ready to work.
그런 다음 일할 준비를 하십시오.
I'm going fishing.
나는 낚시하러 갈거야.
Thanks, Mr. He.
감사합니다, Mr. He.
Well,
음,
last night...
어젯밤...
Last night?
어젯밤?
Well...
음...
You...
당신은...
Me?
나?
We...
우리는...
We?
우리?
Nothing.
아무것도 아님.
I'm just saying
난 그냥 말하는 거야
we were lucky last night.
어젯밤에는 운이 좋았어.
We could've been run over by a car.
우리는 차에 치일 수도 있었어요.
Speaking of which,
말하자면,
my body feels like
내 몸은 다음과 같아
it's been hit by a train.
기차에 치였어.
It's aching everywhere.
여기저기가 아프네요.
Angela, you're totally fine.
안젤라, 정말 괜찮아요.
Really?
정말?
But I just feel like...
하지만 내 기분은...
You know what?
그거 알아?
Something's off here.
뭔가 이상해요.
Can you check it again for me?
다시 확인해 주실 수 있나요?
No need.
필요하지 않습니다.
I've already heard it. It's fine.
나는 이미 그것을 들었습니다. 괜찮습니다.
Look at you.
당신을보세요.
You look great.
당신은 멋져 보인다.
Okay.
좋아요.
I think I look great too.
나도 멋있는 것 같아.
Let me borrow that.
그거 빌리겠습니다.
Let me see if you're okay.
당신이 괜찮은지 좀 볼게요.
What could possibly be wrong with me?
나에게 무슨 문제가 있을 수 있을까요?
Alright, you look great too.
알았어, 너도 정말 좋아 보이는구나.
He doesn't look great.
그 사람 별로 안 좋아 보이는데요.
What's wrong with him?
그 사람에게 무슨 문제가 있습니까?
He...
그는...
What could possibly be wrong with him?
그에게 무슨 문제가 있을 수 있을까요?
Then why is he selling the guesthouse?
그렇다면 그는 왜 게스트하우스를 파는 걸까요?
I'm sorry
미안해요
that I didn't take good care of this home.
내가 이 집을 잘 돌보지 않았다는 걸.
Where's the tape?
테이프는 어디에 있나요?
I told you to find the tape.
테이프를 찾아보라고 했어요.
I couldn't find it.
나는 그것을 찾을 수 없었다.
Then go through
그런 다음
the maps and photo frames
지도와 사진 액자
in the guesthouse.
게스트하우스에서.
Anything that can be recycled, sort it all out
재활용이 가능한 모든 것, 다 정리해
and find a place to take it.
그리고 그것을 가져갈 곳을 찾으세요.
Wait.
기다리다.
We haven't signed the contract yet.
우리는 아직 계약서에 서명하지 않았습니다.
Why are you in such a hurry?
왜 그렇게 서두르나요?
We have to do it sooner or later.
조만간 해야 합니다.
Hurry up. Sort it out.
서둘러요. 정리해보세요.
Get it done.
완료하세요.
What about the guestbook?
방명록은 어떻습니까?
Are you throwing it away too?
너도 버리는 거야?
Xiangyong was the one who bought it.
그것을 구입한 사람은 Xiangyong이었습니다.
I'll wait for him to come back and decide.
나는 그가 돌아와서 결정하기를 기다릴 것이다.
He.
그.
Your VIPs are here.
귀하의 VIP가 여기 있습니다.
You don't have to sell the guesthouse.
게스트하우스를 팔 필요는 없습니다.
Look.
바라보다.
Village Chief Wang alone donated twenty thousand.
왕 촌장 혼자 2천만원을 기부했습니다.
And the guy I ran into outside,
그리고 밖에서 만난 남자는
De from the grocery store,
식료품점에서 온,
gave us all his earnings from yesterday.
어제 벌어들인 돈을 우리에게 다 줬어요.
And Auntie Jiao,
그리고 자오 아줌마님,
who doesn't know how to use the ATM,
ATM 사용법을 모르는 사람
went back home
집으로 돌아갔어
and brought out her dowry.
그리고 지참금을 꺼냈습니다.
This is from Jinfa.
진파에서 온 소식입니다.
And this is from Chunhua.
그리고 이건 춘화에서 온 거예요.
They all donated.
그들은 모두 기부했습니다.
Hua, where's yours?
후아, 네 건 어디 있어?
Mine's already in there.
내 것은 이미 거기에 있어요.
This is a token of our appreciation.
이것은 우리의 감사의 표시입니다.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
But this isn't enough.
그러나 이것만으로는 충분하지 않습니다.
Take it back.
다시 가져가세요.
Now add mine.
이제 내 것을 추가하세요.
Five million.
500만.
There you go.
됐어요.
You can't do that.
당신은 그렇게 할 수 없습니다.
This is everyone's hard-earned money.
모두가 힘들게 벌어들인 돈입니다.
Especially yours.
특히 당신 것.
You worked so hard to raise Wanzhe.
Wanzhe를 키우느라 너무 고생하셨습니다.
This is the pension that you've been saving for years.
이것이 펜션이다 당신이 수년 동안 저장해 놓은 것입니다.
Keep it. Enjoy your retirement.
유지하세요. 은퇴를 즐기십시오.
Don't give it to me.
나한테 주지 마세요.
Don't be silly!
바보같은 소리 하지 마세요!
You and your wife used to
당신과 당신의 아내는
help me take care of Wanzhe every day,
매일 Wanzhe를 돌볼 수 있게 도와주세요
right?
오른쪽?
And listen.
그리고 들어보세요.
Here, this money.
여기, 이 돈.
What?
무엇?
I'm not giving it to you as a gift.
나는 그것을 당신에게 선물로 주는 것이 아닙니다.
I'm lending it to you.
나는 그것을 당신에게 빌려주고 있습니다.
Okay, let me make this clear.
좋아요, 이것을 분명히 하겠습니다.
We're writing an IOU.
우리는 IOU를 작성하고 있습니다.
And we're charging interest.
그리고 우리는 이자를 부과하고 있습니다.
Hey, Xiaoyou.
안녕, 샤오유.
Go get me the ink pad.
가서 잉크 패드를 가져다주세요.
Here.
여기.
Right.
오른쪽.
He, stop being so stubborn.
그 사람, 너무 고집 부리지 마세요.
You know we have so many memories
우리가 추억이 너무 많은 거 알잖아
in this guesthouse.
이 게스트하우스에서.
For Xingpu Island,
싱푸섬의 경우
and for Xiangyong,
그리고 Xiangyong의 경우
just take it.
그냥 가져가세요.
Take it.
가져가세요.
Alright. Alright.
괜찮은. 괜찮은.
What now?
지금은 무엇입니까?
You'd rather sell the guesthouse
차라리 게스트하우스를 팔고 싶으세요
to a stranger
낯선 사람에게
than owe me money?
나한테 빚진 것보다?
Are you looking down on me?
나를 깔보는 거야?
-Is that it? -No, that's not what I meant.
- 그게 다야? -아니, 내 말은 그런 뜻이 아니었어.
No.
아니요.
I owe you so much.
나는 당신에게 너무 많은 빚을 지고 있습니다.
I don't know how I'll ever pay you back.
어떻게 갚을 수 있을지 모르겠습니다.
How?
어떻게?
Work harder and make more money, that's how.
더 열심히 일하고, 더 많은 돈을 벌고, 그게 방법입니다.
If you don't pay me back,
나에게 돈을 갚지 않으면
I'll tear down this house.
나는 이 집을 헐겠다.
Then I'll bring my dog here to pee every day.
그럼 난 내 개를 여기로 데려올게 매일 소변을 보는 것.
And I'll throw away all the flowers
그리고 꽃은 모두 버릴 거예요
that your wife brought!
당신 아내가 가져온 것!
-No!
-아니요!
I'll help pay it back.
갚을 수 있게 도와드릴게요.
It's none of your business.
그것은 당신의 사업이 아닙니다.
I'm your son...
저는 당신의 아들입니다...
Your son's friend.
당신 아들의 친구.
And I'm your employee.
그리고 나는 당신의 직원입니다.
I want to help too.
나도 돕고 싶다.
Awesome!
엄청난!
You're a lucky man.
당신은 운이 좋은 사람입니다.
Your employee is so loyal.
당신의 직원은 매우 충실합니다.
Okay, everything's fine now.
이제 모든 것이 괜찮아졌습니다.
Let's go fishing.
낚시하러 가자.
No, you go ahead.
아니요, 계속하세요.
I already went this morning.
나는 오늘 아침에 이미 갔다.
I'll go throw up.
나는 토하러 갈 것이다.
I told you not to drink too much.
술을 너무 많이 마시지 말라고 했어요.
Now you want to throw up, huh?
이제 토하고 싶죠?
You drank way too much.
당신은 술을 너무 많이 마셨습니다.
You guys are so mushy. That's what makes me want to throw up.
너희들은 너무 부드러워. 그게 내가 토하고 싶게 만드는 이유야.
You guys take care of that money, okay?
너희들이 그 돈을 잘 관리해라, 알았지?
I'll go open up the shop.
제가 가서 가게를 열게요.
Bye.
안녕.
Which way are you trying to go?
어느 쪽으로 가려고 하시나요?
Move!
이동하다!
God, you're so annoying!
맙소사, 너 정말 짜증나!
One more.
하나 더.
Come on.
어서 해봐요.
What's up? You're so quiet.
무슨 일이야? 당신은 너무 조용합니다.
You're here fishing with me.
당신은 나와 함께 낚시를 하고 있습니다.
So I guess you have something on your mind.
그래서 나는 추측한다 당신은 마음 속에 뭔가를 가지고 있습니다.
Uncle Hua,
후아 삼촌,
why are you floating these paper boats?
왜 이 종이배를 떠다니는 걸까요?
I'm saying hello to the dolphins.
돌고래들에게 인사를 하고 있어요.
Dolphins?
돌고래?
When I was a resident at the main island,
내가 본섬에 거주했을 때,
there was a little patient
약간의 환자가 있었어요
who had been in and out of the hospital since childhood.
병원에 드나들었던 사람 어린 시절부터.
He really envied the sea creatures.
그는 정말로 바다 생물들을 부러워했습니다.
Because he thought they could swim wherever they wanted.
그는 그들이 수영을 할 수 있다고 생각했기 때문에 그들이 원하는 곳 어디든.
He even wished that he could be a little dolphin.
그는 심지어 원했다 그 사람이 작은 돌고래가 될 수도 있다는 걸요.
That way, he wouldn't need any more shots or medicine.
그렇게 하면 그 사람은 필요 없을 텐데 주사나 약이 더 필요하지 않습니다.
So I joked with him,
그래서 나는 그 사람과 농담을 했어요.
"Okay.
"알겠습니다.
Then I'll take a boat to come find you."
그럼 제가 배를 타고 당신을 찾으러 갈게요."
So these paper boats
그럼 이 종이배는
hold that kind of memory for you, Uncle Hua.
그런 기억을 당신에게 담아주세요. 화 삼촌.
I wasn't mature enough back then.
그땐 내가 충분히 성숙하지 못했거든요.
I wasn't strong enough to fight for what I believed was right.
나는 충분히 강하지 않았다 내가 옳다고 믿는 것을 위해 싸우기 위해.
So I caused damage that could never be undone.
그래서 피해를 입혔어요 그건 결코 되돌릴 수 없습니다.
And that's why I've stayed on Xingpu Island
그리고 그렇기 때문에 나는 싱푸섬에 머물렀어요
all this time.
이번에는.
What? Are you disappointed?
무엇? 실망하셨나요?
I never had the kind of ambition
난 그런 야망을 가져본 적이 없어
that Schweitzer had, to save humanity.
슈바이처가 인류를 구하기 위해 가졌던 것입니다.
My story is more like
내 이야기는
a coward running away.
에 더 가깝습니다. 도망치는 겁쟁이.
Everyone has their own memories.
사람은 누구나 자신만의 추억을 갖고 있습니다.
I'm not in a position to judge.
나는 판단할 입장이 아니다.
But
하지만
I feel like I just saw my old self.
예전의 제 모습을 본 것 같아요.
If I'd
내가
had more courage
더 용기가 생겼어요
to protect the person who mattered most to me,
그 사람을 보호하기 위해 나에게 가장 중요한 사람은 누구였나요?
maybe things wouldn't be
어쩌면 상황은 그렇지 않을 수도 있어
so complicated now.
지금은 너무 복잡해요.
What's the matter?
무슨 일이야?
Run into some trouble?
문제가 생겼나요?
Anyway,
어쨌든,
the first part of the dream was fuzzy.
꿈의 첫 부분은 흐릿했다.
I only remember,
기억나는 건,
in the end, the handsome guy
결국엔 잘생긴 남자
kissed that loser.
그 패자에게 키스했어요.
And then I woke up.
그리고 나는 일어났습니다.
So you kissed Chen Haowei last night?
그럼 어젯밤에 Chen Haowei에게 키스하셨나요?
I didn't say that.
나는 그렇게 말하지 않았다.
Don't deny it.
그것을 부정하지 마십시오.
We've known each other for so long.
우리는 오랫동안 서로를 알고 있었습니다.
Just tell me who made the first move.
누가 먼저 움직였는지 말해 보세요.
It was me.
나였어.
How's Xiaoyou's reaction?
샤오유의 반응은 어떤가요?
I think I pushed him away.
내가 그를 밀어낸 것 같아요.
I forgot.
잊어버렸어요.
I told you I only remember the kissing part.
말했잖아, 나만 기억난다고 키스하는 부분.
Do you think he was just drunk
그 사람이 그냥 술에 취한 것 같나요
and trying to take advantage of me?
그리고 나를 이용하려고?
No way.
안 돼요.
Is Chen Haowei really that kind of monster?
첸 하오웨이인가? 정말 그런 괴물이야?
You're right.
당신 말이 맞아요.
He's not that kind of person.
그 사람은 그런 사람이 아니거든요.
He was probably drunk and just confessed how he loved you.
아마 술에 취한 것 같았어 그리고 그가 당신을 얼마나 사랑했는지 고백했어요.
Are you talking about me
나에 대해 말하는 거야
or Zhong Xiaoyou?
아니면 종샤오유?
I admit that I have feelings for Xiaoyou.
나는 Xiaoyou에 대한 감정이 있음을 인정합니다.
I think I like him.
나는 그를 좋아하는 것 같아요.
If you like him, just tell him.
당신이 그 사람을 좋아한다면, 그냥 그 사람에게 말하세요.
What's there to worry about?
걱정할 게 뭐가 있나요?
No.
아니요.
I like Xiaoyou
나는 Xiaoyou를 좋아해요
because I thought he was He Xiangyong.
왜냐하면 나는 그가 He Xiangyong이라고 생각했기 때문입니다.
The name I kept calling last night
어젯밤에 계속 불렀던 이름
was He Xiangyong.
허샹용(He Xiangyong)이었습니다.
So he doesn't remember kissing you?
그럼 그 사람은 너한테 키스한 기억이 없다는 거야?
Nope.
아니요.
From how he acted this morning,
오늘 아침 그가 어떻게 행동했는지에 따르면,
it was like he forgot everything.
마치 모든 것을 잊어버린 것 같았습니다.
But if he really likes Xiaoyou,
하지만 그가 Xiaoyou를 정말 좋아한다면
like you said,
네가 말한 대로
then how could he just forget about it?
그렇다면 어떻게 그 일을 잊어버릴 수 있겠는가?
Or maybe he mistook Xiaoyou for you,
아니면 그가 Xiaoyou를 당신으로 착각했을 수도 있습니다.
so he pretended nothing happened.
그래서 그는 아무 일도 일어나지 않은 척했습니다.
What a jerk.
정말 바보입니다.
That's why I can't
그래서 난 할 수 없어
confess to Xiaoyou.
Xiaoyou에게 고백하십시오.
Because I know
나는 알고 있기 때문에
they are not the same person.
그들은 같은 사람이 아닙니다.
I may have confused them before,
이전에 혼동했을 수도 있습니다.
but
하지만
the person on my mind is Xiangyong.
내 마음 속에 있는 사람은 Xiangyong입니다.
I can't treat Xiaoyou as his replacement.
나는 Xiaoyou를 그의 대체자로 대할 수 없습니다.
Well, if that's the case,
그렇다면,
I think you should stick with it.
나는 당신이 그것을 고수해야한다고 생각합니다.
Don't start the wrong kind of relationship.
시작하지 마세요 잘못된 종류의 관계.
Otherwise,
그렇지 않으면
Xiaoyou is going to get really hurt.
샤오유는 정말 상처받을 거예요.
That's not right.
그건 옳지 않아요.
Whether it's Zhong Xiaoyou or He Xiangyong,
종샤오유인지 또는 He Xiangyong,
you are still you.
당신은 여전히 ​​당신입니다.
It's just like snow cone and shaved ice.
마치 스노우 콘과 빙수와 같습니다.
Same thing, just different names.
똑같은데 이름만 다를 뿐이죠.
That's some crazy logic you've got.
그것은 당신이 가지고 있는 미친 논리입니다.
But it seems to make sense.
그러나 그것은 의미가 있는 것 같습니다.
Now that you mention it,
이제 언급하셨으니,
Chen Haowei has always been devoted to you.
Chen Haowei는 항상 당신에게 헌신했습니다.
It's so romantic.
정말 로맨틱해요.
Are you going to accept him?
당신은 그 사람을 받아들일 건가요?
Accept what?
무엇을 받아들이나요?
And as who?
그리고 누구로서?
As me?
나처럼?
Or as Zhong Xiaoyou?
아니면 종샤오유(Zhong Xiaoyou)로?
Besides,
게다가,
I have nothing left to tear apart.
나에게는 찢을 것이 하나도 남지 않았습니다.
Dude, can you please talk like a normal person?
친구, 부탁 좀 해줄래? 보통 사람처럼 말해요?
But look.
하지만 보세요.
Our wishes just came true like that.
우리의 소원은 그렇게 이루어졌습니다.
Don't you feel it's a bit unsettling?
좀 불안한 느낌이 들지 않나요?
It's like
그것은 마치
if you find a million bucks on the street
길거리에서 백만 달러를 발견하면
and bring it home,
집으로 가져와
would you really be happy?
정말 행복할까?
Li Wanzhe!
리완체!
Hama-chan, you're not going out to sea today?
하마짱, 너 오늘 바다에 안 갈 거야?
I quit my job!
나는 직장을 그만뒀다!
I'll be working here from now on!
나 이제부터 여기서 일할 거야!
Let's work well together!
우리 같이 잘 일하자!
Tell me.
말해 주세요.
Why did you quit?
왜 그만두셨나요?
Did something happen?
무슨 일이 있었나요?
Or did Bingzhong bully you?
아니면 Bingzhong이 당신을 괴롭혔습니까?
Your face is so funny.
당신 얼굴이 참 웃기네요.
You look just like Bingzhong.
당신은 Bingzhong과 꼭 닮았습니다.
Hamaguchi Soukai.
하마구치 소우카이.
I'm trying to be serious with you.
나는 당신에게 진지하게 대하려고 노력하고 있습니다.
Don't worry.
괜찮아요.
I'm fine.
잘 지내요.
No one bullied me.
아무도 나를 괴롭히지 않았습니다.
I quit my job
직장을 그만뒀어요
because of you.
당신 때문에.
Me?
나?
Yes.
예.
Last night, you told me
어젯밤에 네가 나한테 말했어
that you wanted to stay with me and have fun every day.
당신이 나와 함께 머물고 싶어했다고 그리고 매일 즐겁게 지내세요.
So I quit my job.
그래서 직장을 그만뒀어요.
That way, I can be with you every day.
그래야 내가 매일 너와 함께 있을 수 있어.
When did I say that?
내가 언제 그런 말을 했나요?
You forgot?
잊었나요?
Let me remind you.
상기시켜 드리겠습니다.
You said it while holding me like this.
이렇게 나를 안고서 말했잖아.
I'm so happy.
정말 기뻐요.
It's so warm.
너무 따뜻해요.
I wish we could be together like this
우리 이렇게 함께 있었으면 좋겠어
every day.
매일.
Well?
잘?
Does it feel familiar?
익숙한 느낌이 드나요?
People talk nonsense when they're drunk.
사람들은 술에 취하면 말도 안되는 소리를 합니다.
How could you take it seriously?
어떻게 진지하게 받아들일 수 있나요?
I told you.
내가 말했잖아.
I'll do everything I can
나는 내가 할 수 있는 모든 것을 할 것이다
when it comes to you.
당신에 관해서는.
But
하지만
you said
네가 말했지
being a sailor was your dream.
선원이 되는 것이 당신의 꿈이었어요.
You said you wanted to travel the world.
세계를 여행하고 싶다고 하더군요.
From now on,
이제부터
you are my dream.
당신은 내 꿈입니다.
You are my whole world.
당신은 내 세상의 전부입니다.
Boss, I'm heading to work now.
선생님, 저는 지금 회사에 갑니다.
What do you need to write? I can write it for you.
무엇을 써야 합니까? 나는 당신을 위해 그것을 쓸 수 있습니다.
Okay, you write the words.
좋아요, 당신이 단어를 쓰세요.
No drawing, alright?
그림은 안 그려요, 그렇죠?
I'm saving that for Xiangyong when he comes back.
Xiangyong을 위해 아껴두겠습니다 그가 돌아올 때.
He made such a mess
그 사람이 정말 엉망으로 만들었어
and just disappeared.
그리고 방금 사라졌습니다.
Aren't you angry?
화나지 않았나요?
Why are you still doing all this for him?
왜 아직도 그 사람을 위해 이런 짓을 하는 거죠?
I am angry.
나는 화가 났다.
I'm angry at myself
나 자신에게 화가 났어
for not teaching him how to box when he was little.
그 사람을 가르치지 않아서 어렸을 때 권투하는 법.
Because of that,
그 때문에
he can only hold it in when he's wronged.
그 사람은 참을 수 밖에 없어 그가 부당한 일을 당했을 때.
Are you worried about him?
그 사람이 걱정되나요?
Aren't you afraid that he might not come back?
두렵지 않나요? 그 사람이 돌아오지 못할까봐?
Of course I am.
물론이죠.
But he has his reasons.
그러나 그에게는 이유가 있습니다.
Anyway, his home and his dad are here.
어쨌든 그의 집과 아버지는 여기 있어요.
He can come back whenever he wants.
그는 원할 때마다 돌아올 수 있습니다.
If he finds out
그가 알아낸다면
that you almost
거의
sold the guesthouse for him,
그를 위해 게스트하우스를 팔았어
he'll definitely come drink with me for three days straight.
그 사람은 꼭 나랑 술 마시러 올 거야 3일 연속.
And he'll cry, saying how immature he's been.
그리고 그는 울 것이다. 그가 얼마나 미성숙했는지 말이에요.
This is heavy.
이건 무겁다.
He can't even drink.
그는 술도 못마십니다.
You don't know?
모르시나요?
His way of curing a hangover is climbing a mountain.
그의 숙취 해소법 산을 오르고 있어요.
Once he reaches the top, he can see the ocean
일단 그가 정상에 도달하면, 그는 바다를 볼 수 있어
and Xingpu Island.
그리고 싱푸섬.
When did he start drinking?
그는 언제부터 술을 마시기 시작했나요?
After he started working.
그가 일을 시작한 후.
That brat.
그 녀석.
He'll go out and drink with others,
그는 나가서 다른 사람들과 함께 술을 마실 것이다
but he won't even have one with me at home.
하지만 그 사람은 나한테도 한 명도 없을 거야 집에서.
He just doesn't want you
그 사람은 당신을 원하지 않을 뿐이에요
to see his weak side.
그의 약한 면을 보기 위해.
When he's drunk,
그가 술에 취했을 때,
he talks too much, acts like a kid, and cries a lot.
그 사람은 말을 너무 많이 해요. 어린아이처럼 행동하고 많이 운다.
I bet you don't like that.
나는 당신이 그것을 좋아하지 않을 것이라고 확신합니다.
It's nothing.
그것은 아무것도 아니다.
He takes after me.
그는 나를 따라갑니다.
In his eyes,
그의 눈에는
I'm just a bad-tempered father
난 그냥 성격이 나쁜 아버지일 뿐이야
who's not worth sharing his thoughts with.
자신의 생각을 공유할 가치가 없는 사람.
It's not like that.
그렇지 않습니다.
He knows
그는 알고 있어
that everything you do is for his own good.
당신이 하는 모든 일이 자신의 이익을 위한 것입니다.
He just
그는 단지
doesn't know how to express it.
어떻게 표현해야 할지 모르겠습니다.
Then I was right to keep that chalkboard.
그렇다면 제가 그 칠판을 갖고 있는 것이 옳았습니다.
Xiangyong has always been a sensitive kid.
Xiangyong은 항상 예민한 아이였습니다.
His drawings
그의 그림
are probably his way of showing how he feels.
아마 그의 방식일 거야 그가 어떻게 느끼는지 보여주는 것입니다.
By the way,
그런데,
tell him
그에게 말해
that his dad only hates one type of drinker.
그 사람 아빠가 제일 싫어하는 건 술꾼의 한 종류.
The type who makes a scene when they're drunk.
장면을 만드는 유형 술에 취했을 때.
Isn't that you?
당신이 아닌가요?
Shut up.
입 다물어.
When he comes back,
그가 돌아오면
why don't you just ask him for a drink yourself?
그냥 하지 그래? 그에게 직접 술 한잔 해달라고 부탁해?
I'll be the chef today.
오늘은 내가 셰프가 될 거예요.
I'll make you some drinking snacks
술안주 만들어줄게
and your favorite garlic shrimp vermicelli.
그리고 당신이 가장 좋아하는 마늘 새우 당면.
You know how?
어떻게 하는지 알아?
Of course I do.
물론이죠.
That's Xiangyong's mother's special dish.
바로 샹용 어머니의 특선 요리입니다.
You know how to cook it?
당신은 그것을 요리하는 방법을 알고 있나요?
He taught me.
그는 나에게 가르쳤다.
You can't cook it.
당신은 그것을 요리할 수 없습니다.
But you're lucky.
하지만 당신은 운이 좋다.
Because I can.
왜냐하면 나는 할 수 있기 때문이다.
I'll cook for you.
내가 요리해줄게.
I know how to do it. Don't worry.
나는 그것을하는 방법을 알고 있습니다. 괜찮아요.
I'm confident, okay?
난 자신있어, 알았지?
Young man,
젊은이여,
I'm starting to wonder
궁금해지기 시작했어
about your relationship with my son.
당신과 내 아들의 관계에 대해서요.
We're just friends.
우리는 단지 친구입니다.
The kind that tell each other everything.
서로에게 모든 것을 말하는 타입.
No.
아니요.
He even taught you that?
그 사람이 너한테 그런 것도 가르쳤어?
You know how to cook it?
당신은 그것을 요리하는 방법을 알고 있나요?
Are you sure you know how to cook it?
요리하는 방법을 확실히 알고 있나요?
I'm sure.
나는 확신한다.
Is the oil hot enough?
기름이 충분히 뜨겁나요?
Just wait for it.
그냥 기다리세요.
Wait for it.
기다리세요.
It's almost there.
거의 다 왔습니다.
The shrimp
새우
and the vermicelli.
그리고 당면.
Don't let the oil get too hot,
기름을 너무 뜨거워지지 마세요,
or the garlic will burn, you know?
안 그러면 마늘이 타버릴 거예요. 아시죠?
I know. Just fry it a little.
알아요. 살짝 볶아주시면 됩니다.
Don't fry it too long.
너무 오래 튀기지 마세요.
Hurry up and add the chili.
빨리 고추를 추가하세요.
Hurry.
서두르다.
It's fine.
괜찮습니다.
This is how I've always done it, okay?
난 항상 이렇게 해왔어, 알았지?
That's not gonna work.
그건 작동하지 않을 것입니다.
Trust me. It's fine.
나를 믿으세요. 괜찮습니다.
I can't watch this.
나는 이것을 볼 수 없다.
Here, move over.
여기로 이동하세요.
Please.
제발.
Go stand aside.
가서 옆으로 서세요.
I told you. I'm cooking today.
내가 말했잖아. 나는 오늘 요리를 하고 있다.
Go make the sauce for me, okay?
가서 소스 좀 만들어 줘, 알았지?
Please. Thank you.
제발. 감사합니다.
Not bad.
나쁘지 않아요.
You need to throw that out quickly.
그거 빨리 버려야 해요.
Otherwise,
그렇지 않으면
add some water.
물을 좀 추가하세요.
[Hope you're doing well. This is a really wonderful place. Haowei]
[잘 지내길 바라. 이곳은 정말 멋진 곳이에요. 하오웨이]
Chen Haowei.
첸 하오웨이.
It's almost done.
거의 다 끝났습니다.
Time to eat.
먹을 시간입니다.
What are you doing?
뭐하세요?
If you happen to run into He Xiangyong,
He Xiangyong을 만나게 된다면,
give this to him for me.
나를 위해 이것을 그 사람에게 주세요.
I'll go help Mr. He now.
지금 당장 그 씨를 도우러 가겠습니다.
[He Xiangyong]
[허샹용]
[Epilogue]
[에필로그]
Chen Haowei.
첸 하오웨이.
What are you doing?
뭐하세요?
I'm waiting for someone.
나는 누군가를 기다리고 있습니다.
Are you waiting for me?
나를 기다리고 있나요?
Just kidding.
농담이에요.
I saw you looking at the drawing.
나는 당신이 그림을 보고 있는 것을 보았습니다.
Yes.
예.
Can I see it?
볼 수 있나요?
Let me take a look.
좀 살펴 보겠습니다.
Okay.
좋아요.
A sea turtle!
바다거북!
Yeah. I really like sea turtles.
응. 저는 바다거북을 정말 좋아해요.
Did He Xiangyong draw this?
허샹용이 그린건가요?
Yeah. Why?
응. 왜?
Don't you think
그렇게 생각하지 않나요
his childlike touch is kind of ugly?
그의 어린애같은 손길이 좀 못생겼다고요?
What's that?
그게 뭐야?
No wonder you were laughing.
당신이 웃고 있었던 것도 당연합니다.
This is what you were laughing at.
이것이 당신이 웃었던 것입니다.
Well, yeah.
글쎄요.
I think it's worth laughing at.
웃을 가치가 있다고 생각합니다.
Yeah, I think so too.
네, 저도 그렇게 생각해요.
Let me tell you.
내가 당신에게 말해 보자.
He Xiangyong is a really,
He Xiangyong은 정말,
really strange person.
정말 이상한 사람.
No one in our class likes him.
우리 반에 그를 좋아하는 사람은 아무도 없어요.
But I think you're really kind.
그런데 정말 친절하신 것 같아요.
You still spend time being his friend
당신은 아직도 그 사람의 친구로 지내는 데 시간을 보내고 있어요
and help him with his homework and stuff.
그의 숙제 같은 것을 도와주세요.
Yeah, just helping a classmate.
응, 그냥 같은 반 친구를 돕는 것 뿐이야.
So you think he needs help too?
그럼 그 사람도 도움이 필요하다고 생각하시나요?
Then we are very similar.
그렇다면 우리는 매우 비슷합니다.
We both help people
우리 둘 다 사람들을 돕습니다
who seem like they need it.
필요하다고 생각되는 사람.
Can you do me a favor?
부탁 하나만 들어줄 수 있나요?
What is it?
그것은 무엇입니까?
I want to borrow it.
나는 그것을 빌리고 싶다.
Just let me borrow it. I'll give it back next week.
그냥 빌려주세요. 다음 주에 돌려드릴게요.
Aren't you in the art class?
너 미술시간에 있지 않니?
You can draw it yourself, right?
직접 그릴 수도 있죠?
Class is starting. I gotta go.
수업이 시작됩니다. 난 가야 해.
Chen Haowei says he's tired.
Chen Haowei는 피곤하다고 말했습니다.
You know Chen Haowei
Chen Haowei 아시죠
is a popular student in the school.
학교에서 인기가 많은 학생이에요.
He has a lot of friends.
그는 친구가 많습니다.
And everyone likes him.
그리고 모두가 그를 좋아해요.
So any event,
그럼 어떤 이벤트든,
any club...
어떤 클럽이든...
What are you trying to say?
무슨 말을 하려는 걸까요?
I'm just saying
난 그냥 말하는 거야
Chen Haowei's grades have dropped.
Chen Haowei의 성적이 떨어졌습니다.
And he's been dozing off in class.
그리고 그 사람은 수업 시간에 졸고 있었어요.
You think it's my fault?
그게 내 잘못이라고 생각해요?
I didn't say that.
나는 그렇게 말하지 않았다.
Why do you have to think the worst of me?
왜 나를 최악으로 생각해야합니까?
Based on the fact
사실을 토대로
that we're both good friends of Chen Haowei,
우리 둘 다 좋은 친구라는 걸 Chen Haowei의
I want to offer a suggestion
제안하고 싶어요
that would help both you and him.
그게 당신과 그 사람 모두에게 도움이 될 거예요.
Haven't you considered going to a cram school?
고려하지 않았나요? 학원에 갈래?
No need.
필요하지 않습니다.
I won't bother Chen Haowei anymore.
더 이상 Chen Haowei를 괴롭히지 않겠습니다.
Why are you being like that?
왜 그런 짓을 하는 거야?
I'm just saying
난 그냥 말하는 거야
that I was also influenced by Chen Haowei.
나도 Chen Haowei의 영향을 받았다고.
So I want to work with him
그래서 그 사람과 함께 일하고 싶어요
to help classmates like you who are falling behind.
당신 같은 반 친구들을 돕기 위해 뒤처지고 있는 사람.
Let's work harder
더 열심히 해보자
and get better together. Wouldn't that be great?
그리고 함께 나아지세요. 정말 좋지 않을까요?
No need.
필요하지 않습니다.
I'm tired.
피곤해요.
I don't want to work harder.
나는 더 열심히 일하고 싶지 않습니다.
He Xiangyong.
허샹용.
If there's anything
무슨 일이라도 있으면
you need help with,
you need help with,
you can always tell me.
도움이 필요해요
Really.
당신은 언제든지 나에게 말할 수 있습니다.
Just let me know.
정말.
[Next Episode]
그냥 알려주세요.
If you want to go see him off,
[다음 에피소드]
you can still make it to the pier.
그를 배웅하러 가고 싶다면
The person I can't let go of is He Xiangyong.
아직 부두까지 갈 수 있어요.
The person I've always loved is also He Xiangyong.
버릴 수 없는 사람 허샹용(He Xiangyong)이다.
You don't need to turn yourself into He Xiangyong for me.
내가 늘 사랑했던 사람 허샹용(He Xiangyong)도 마찬가지다.
Li Wanzhe.
몸을 돌릴 필요는 없어 나를 위해 He Xiangyong으로.
Are you hungry?
리완체.
You've been working hard all day.
배고프나요?
Let me make you some late-night snacks.
하루 종일 열심히 일하셨어요.